Finding Aid for Charles B. Mears Lumber Company (Ludington, Mich.) records, 1837-1895
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Charles B. Mears Lumber Company (Ludington, Mich.) records 1837-1895
Charles B. Mears Lumber Company (Ludington, Mich.).
12 volumes (in 1 box) and 8 oversize volumes
851815 Bb.2; BB.2 Outsize
Ludington, Michigan lumber company; business records, including day books, inventories, time books, and ledgers.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The records were donated by Carrie E. Mears (donor no. 1072 ).
No further additions to the records are expected.
The record group is open to research.
The Charles B. Mears Lumber Company was based in Ludington, Michigan. The company operated various camps and mills in Mason, Muskegon, and Oceana counties. Mears' first lumbering venture was in the area around White Lake, Michigan.
The record group consists of financial records from the various camps and mills which Charles Mears owned in Mason, Muskegon, and Oceana counties. The earliest record is an account book, 1837-1843, showing expenditures from his first lumbering venture near White Lake, Michigan.
Subjects:
Mears, Charles B., 1814-1895.; Business records.; Duck Lake (Mich.); General stores--Michigan.; Lincoln (Mason County, Mich.); Ludington (Mich.); Logging--Michigan.; Lumbering--Michigan.; Mason County (Mich.); Mears (Mich.); Muskegon County (Mich.); Oceana County (Mich.); Pentwater (Mich.); Silver Lake (Oceana County, Mich.); White Lake (Muskegon County, Mich.); Charles B. Mears Lumber Company (Ludington, Mich.)
- Business records
  - Duck Lake Day Book, 1871-1872 (Box 1)
  - Time Book [Mears, Mich.] 1879-1892 (Box 1)
  - Inventory of Mears Store, 1895, 2 volumes (Box 1)
  - Inventory of Pentwater Store, 1895, 2 volumes (Box 1)
  - Cash Blotter, 1862-1866 (Box 1)
  - Duck Lake Cash Account, 1863-1869 (Box 1)
  - Duck Lake Cash Blotter, 1859-1862 (Box 1)
  - Hamline Mills Time Book, 1860-1863 (Box 1)
  - Time Book, 1868-1883 (Box 1)
  - Duck Lake Sales Book, 1880-1882 (Box 1)
  - Duck Lake Ledger, 1865-1868 (Volume 5)
    (oversize volume no. 5)
  - White River Day Book, 1850-1853 (Volume 1)
    (oversize volume no. 1)
  - Account book, 1837-1845 (Volume 7)
    (oversize volume no. 7)
  - Middlesex Ledger, 1864-1865 (Volume 2)
    (oversize volume no. 2)
  - Middlesex Day Book, 1866-1867 (Volume 6)
    (oversize volume no. 6)
  - Middlesex Day Book, 1867-1869 (Volume 4)
    (oversize volume no. 4)
  - Lincoln, Mason County Day Book, 1861-1863 (Volume 8)
    (oversize volume no. 8)
  - Lincoln, Mason County, Day Book, 1868-1870 (Volume 3)
    (oversize volume no. 3)
Related Material
The library also has a collection of the personal and political papers of Charles B. Mears.